## **Matt Prestlien**

+1 (360) 303-6901 me@mattprestlien.com http://mattprestlien.com/

**Denver, CO 80223** 

Profile

Professional and versatile engineer with a penchant for user-focused design hailing from veteran SaaS firms. Experience and acute interest in web app development and design, specifically with React/Angular and hybrid frameworks for mobile. Works proficiently alone and adeptly within group or team dynamics, coupled with excellent time management skills and attention to detail.

Experience

Full-Stack Software Developer, SCRAM Systems; Littleton, CO - 2018-Present

Tasked with building an offender-facing application for parole management, I chose lonic/ Capacitor for accelerated mobile development with <u>ASP.net</u> Core services and Azure Functions on the backend. Architected a strong Angular application using TypeScript and RxJS + NgRx. Built out CI pipelines for the mobile app to take load off the DevOps team. Worked on unit testing and UI testing initiatives using Jest and BrowserStack. Chose AuthO for a managed authentication solution reducing infrastructure overhead. Hired and trained a junior developer to assist with regular influx of work. Troubleshot both native issues for iOS/ Android as well as problems with Azure. Explored aspects of domain-driven and event-driven design to ensure a cohesive UX. Helped coach UI/UX team to improve design-dev workflow and created a frontend focused cross-cutting group within the org to disseminate knowledge. Cordova Engineer, SpiderOak; Kansas City, MO (Remote) - 2016-2018

Focused on building an end-to-end encrypted enterprise chat application. Cordova expertise applied to quickly and efficiently solve performance/UX issues and implement features with advanced CSS tactics. Helped the team to create a React/Redux mobile app while maintaining an organized codebase responsive enough to use on the desktop via Electron. Software Engineer, ServiceMonster; Bellingham, WA - 2014-2016

Translated an <u>ASP.net</u> MVC application to a mobile app, choosing frameworks and technologies carefully to ensure that the product could be built rapidly and efficiently while still ensuring an intuitive end-user experience. Tasked with hiring team members and supporting them with appropriate training & project management software.

Education

Associate in Liberal Studies, Whatcom Community College; Bellingham, WA - 2012-2015

Skills

## Languages and Frameworks

Mature problem-solving skills and engineering process. Worked extensively in Javascript and C#, as well as Swift and Java, primarily within the context of mobile front-ends and their RESTful web services. Demonstrable deep understanding of single-state application flow via Redux/NgRx as well as an MVC paradigm via standard Angular.

## Communication

Work methodically with a team of individuals in order to achieve a common goal while keeping stakeholder input in mind. Adept with peer review, refactoring and building specs to ensure development projects are well-maintained. Projects have been commended by peers for their accuracy to mockups while ensuring strong code hygiene.

**Technologies** 

- Angular/React
- Sass/CSS Modules
- C#/<u>ASP.net</u> Core
- ES6+/Typescript
- Webpack
- Cordova/Electron
- JIRA/VSTS
- AWS/Azure
- · Bash Scripting for CI